Elizabeth Jarvis Raymond Papers
Connecticut Historical Society
Elizabeth Jarvis Raymond Papers.
1866-1963
Connecticut Historical Society
Raymond, Elizabeth Jarvis
Collection consists of correspondence of the Banks and Raymond families of Norwalk, Connecticut.
10 folders (1 envelope)
Biographical Sketch
Elizabeth Jarvis Raymond was born in Norwalk, Connecticut in 1881, the daughter of George Henry and Helen Eugenia Banks Raymond and granddaughter of Bradley and Rachel Jarvis Banks and Elizabeth Beers Raymond. She graduated from Centre High School in Norwalk in 1897. She was a Civil Service employee in Washington, D.C. until she retired in l944 at which time she moved to Hartford, Connecticut.
Scope and Content
Collection consists largely of correspondence of the Banks and Raymond families and includes a map of the Archer-Beers homestead and postcards depicting homes and buildings in Norwalk, Connecticut.
Arrangement
Materials are organized into four series based on arrangement by the donor.
Series I: Map of Archer-Beers Homestead consists of two identical maps of the Archer-Beers homestead in Norwalk, Connecticut showing Wolf Pit Hill Road and Strawberry Lane; one map is on architect's linen, the other is a blueprint.
Series II: Correspondence of the Banks Family contains letters to each other from members of the Banks family of Norwalk, Connecticut, including one on the letterhead of Rocky Dell Institute in Lime Rock, Connecticut in 1875 and one the letterhead of S. E. Olmstead & Co., proprietors of the Norwalk Foundry in 1879.
Series III: Papers of Elizabeth Jarvis Raymond consists of correspondence and papers of Elizabeth Jarvis Raymond on family matters, including certificates of vaccination, United States passports, postcards and photographs of buildings in Norwalk, Connecticut and notes on a prize presented by the Norwalk Chapter of the Daughters of the American Revolution in 1896 for an essay on Norwalk in the American Revolution.
Series IV: Genealogical Notes on the Jarvis, Sanford, Banks and Raymond Families comprises transcriptions of information in family Bibles, printed genealogies and correspondence about the Jarvis, Sanford, Banks and Raymond families
Materials are arranged chronologically within each series.
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions on access to the collection.
Accruals
The collection is open, additional material is not expected.
Subject Headings:
Family Names
Banks Family.; Jarvis Family.; Raymond Family.; Sanford Family.
Subjects
Genealogy.
Geographic Names
Norwalk (Conn.) -- Buildings; Norwalk (Conn.) -- Maps
Contents:
- I. Map of Archer-Beers Homestead
  - Map of the Archer-Beers Homestead., undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- II. Correspondence of the Banks Family
  - Correspondence of the Banks Family, 1866-1879 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence of the Banks Family, 1880-1891 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- III. Papers of Elizabeth Jarvis Raymond
  - Correspondence of Elizabeth Jarvis Raymond, 1924-1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Legal Papers of Elizabeth Jarvis Raymond, 1948-1963 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Postcards and Photographs, 1911-1947 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Memorabilia, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- IV. Genealogical Notes on the Jarvis, Sanford, Banks and Raymond Families
  - Genealogical Notes on the Jarvis, Sanford, Banks and Raymond Families (Box 1, Folder 8)